What's wrong?
I'm wondering if
everyone else is safe.
There are a lot of people in the east
who have the same skin color as you,
so I think they were
able to slip in.
However, you are seen as the
instigator of the rebellion in Liore.
That looks like the temple of the Lord Leto, back in Liore.
It is from an even older religion.
It's no longer being
practiced now, though.
Yes. They only recognized one god
and considered all other gods
to be heathen.
It's said they had
a lot of believers.
Many people died because of it.
A great many.
That's awful.
Religions exist to save people.
People cannot become gods, after all.
There, there. It's all right.
Why did you let
those two get away?
It was your duty to eliminate the brothers, wasn't it, Sloth?
You too, Wrath.
I'll get them next time.
You defied that
certain someone's word.
Sloth, don't you want
to become human?
Yes, I do.
After all, I was born
to become human.
I don't have any other goal.
They're here.
The Philosopher's Stone.
Those who obtain it are set free from the Law of Equivalent Exchange.
There is no need to pay a price
in order to obtain something, either.
We sought it and found it.
Why did you run off on your own
without coming to me for protection?!
Elric brothers, what happened?
King Bradley is...
a homunculus.
By homunculus, you mean those...
man-made people, right?
Yeah.
They are covertly
manipulating this country
in order to get a
Philosopher's Stone.
That's not possible.
The Führer did not know what was taking place at the 5th Laboratory.
He also lamented the corruption within the military.
But I saw it!
The Führer had the
mark of the Uroboros!
There was the one homunculus who can change his shape.
The Führer's secretary is also a homunculus.
And yet, she's an alien...
Supposing that the Führer and
Secretary Douglas are homunculi,
what is their objective?
Why have they
infiltrated the military?
I will send them back to Liore.
I'll come up with an
appropriate reason
for them not to return to Central for a little while.
You do that. As for us...
You're going to Resembool, right?
Gentlemen, rejoice!
Our duties are at an end!
Major, what were you
just talking about?
Were you listening to the melody
being played by this body of mine?
No, not that...
Listen closely!
Hear that? Hear that?
Um...
How is Lieutenant Havoc?
He's okay. He and Fuery
were sent back ahead of us.
I see...
I'm sorry about all that.
Ed, your silver watch...
That's right. You can't be
a State Alchemist anymore,
if what you said earlier is true.
No, it's not that.
I mean, it was taken
from me by Archer.
Huh? Didn't Al-kun
give it back to you?
I-I'm sorry! Brother,
I don't have it anymore!
You lost it?!
N-No! Kimbly threw it at Scar-san,
and all the red stones inside it
came spilling out.
Then they were absorbed into Scar-san's arm.
Why were there red stones inside my silver watch?
That miserable Archer.
He used that trick again,
calling them transmutation amplifiers.
What?
Previously, in Ishbal, Brig. Gen. Grand
supplied us with red stones.
Hold on, Colonel.
Then you knew that the military
was making Philosopher's Stones?
And yet, you didn't
say anything to me?!
When Marcoh deserted,
I thought it had been discontinued.
Besides, it's not as though I knew that people were used as ingredients.
I can't trust you!
Brother!
You couldn't forget about those red stones,
so you tried to send us out to find them!
Stop it, Brother!
Enough already!
Brother!
Al!
Al can't go in the water!
Al! Al!
Al!
Yes?!
Brother! I can swim!
I can swim, Brother!
You idiot!
Your bloodseal washes off if you're submerged in water, doesn't it?
Yeah...
Looks like I don't
have to worry about that.
I wonder if that's because I really
have become a Philosopher's Stone.
O-Okay, I get it! Come on!
What did you just...
It's nothing...
What...
did you just say about
the Philosopher's Stone?
Nothing at all, nothing at all!
Okay, let's get going!
Brother! Wait!
Looks like the military
hasn't arrived yet.
Huh? Sergeant Brosh?
He's in pursuit?
N-No, that's not it. Not him.
Brosh-san?
What's wrong, exactly?
Lieutenant Ross is... Lieutenant Ross is...
Your hair is as deep black
as the feathers
of the great eagles I saw, so long ago.
I never thought I would see anything so beautiful again.
Your flattery is far too kind.
The Lieutenant, single-minded to her work, has gone absolutely sentimental over him!
Of all the things it could have been...
Good for her.
But who is she with, Brother?
Huh?
What are you flirting with her for?!
Edward-san!
You don't come home for umpteen years,
and this is how I find you?!
You rotten old man!
Dad?
Yeah... Just like in the picture...
Dad!
It's Dad! It's Dad!
Um, you probably don't know who I am in this form,
but I'm...
Alphonse! You've gotten bigger, huh?
You know who I am?
Edward...
You still hate milk, don't you?
Who are you saying hasn't grown one bit since he was a baby?!
That's not what he said.
Are you sure, Edward-san?
I'm sure, I'm sure.
Don't get me wrong.
I was just listening to
the stories of his travels.
Still, you did look like you were enjoying it.
Well, he is such a gentleman.
With a whiff of his cologne
subtly carrying on the breeze,
he's not the type of man we get in the military.
Cologne doesn't suit me, anyhow...
Why are you acting so coy?
Cologne, huh?
I hated that about him, too.
He left home
soon after Al was born.
Mom always said he was off studying alchemy,
but he never once
even sent us a letter.
And yet, the scent of that cologne he wore
always permeated the house.
Earlier, when I saw Lyra in Liore,
she was wearing perfume that had the same scent.
You saw Lyra-san?!
Then she must have safely
gotten away from Dante-san's place!
Just a moment, if you please.
This Lyra-san—what kind of
relationship do you two have?
Oh, sorry.
Winry-san, what are you...
Why are you holding that wrench?
I'm sorry.
The Führer is married,
and he also has children.
Above all else, I've seen pictures of him when he was younger.
Homunculi do not take on the form of humans when they are born.
When they are given red stones as a source of nourishment,
they get their own unique powers, as well as their form.
They use people's lives as food?
They can probably alter their appearance
little by little, to make it look like they are aging.
His children could be adopted.
However...
whatever the case,
he's a homunculus.
How do you mean?
You said they were making red stones
in the 5th Laboratory, right?
Homunculi cannot use alchemy.
Yet how is it that they can
teach others how to make them?
You mean, there's someone who raises them and controls them?
Still...
even though they are homunculi,
the country is managing
to get on all right,
and the military is functioning.
We need not concern
ourselves with them.
Why is it that the homunculi can't use alchemy?
Because they come from
the other side of the gate.
But let's not talk about that. Tell me all about Trisha,
as well as everything you guys have been struggling through.
Dad...
I can tell just by looking
at your body. You guys—
There isn't anything to talk about.
Our alchemy failed, and we lost our arms, legs, and bodies. That's all.
Edward, alchemy is not something—
Shut up! Don't you come home now and try to put on a fatherly face!
Mom waited for you
that whole time!
Al, get in here!
Brother!
Brother, I'm sleeping with Dad.
Al...
Let's go, Dad.
I wonder if I can get my body back
with the Philosopher's Stone.
You could attach your soul to someone else's body with the Philosopher's Stone.
Someone else's body?
That's not what I meant. I...
Your own body was lost in an equivalent exchange.
You must have given up your body as the cost of obtaining something else.
Something else?
If you return all of that,
it will come back.
So then, if we can defeat that homunculus...
Nothing, nothing!
You're amazing, Dad!
You know what?
There's something
I want to ask you.
Okay.
Dad?
If I'd known this, I would have
beat him up even more yesterday.
Stop joking around, and hurry
and come look for him with me!
I bet he's just gone off on
some other journey again.
Fine, then I'll go by myself.
Hold it!
You can't leave here
for a little while.
We just got word from Warrant Officer Falman, who was waiting at the train station.
The search party has arrived.
We're going to go over there and send them back.
You sure you want to be harboring wanted men?
It's not as though I believe every aspect of your story.
I plan on ascertaining the truth
about the Führer in my own way.
And if you find out
that it is true?
Now then...
Well now, how about you go down
into the underground cellar for me?
No, that's okay!
You too.
Where could Dad have gone?
You be quiet. More importantly,
how does the Colonel intend to
find out who the Führer really is?
His secretary could only have been around for about four years, right?
Right.
If you mean Juliet Douglas,
she's supposed to have been in the military
for at least fourteen years.
There's no way that could be true.
I'm sure of it. After all, she was
the cause of the Ishbalan Civil War.
Yeah, you mean when that soldier accidentally shot a civilian?
That was a lie.
The cause of the outbreak of the war in Ishbal
was manufactured by
a secret military squad.
They couldn't have...
So that's it! Ishbal was also used for a Philosopher's Stone.
If they could drive
the Ishbalans to war...
...then maybe there was someone
who would make a Philosopher's Stone
using the Grand Art.
Would they go that far?
The homunculi were behind it all.
So that's it. And Hughes-san
must have realized that much
and was killed for it.
Jerk us around, will you?! Colonel, you bastard!
Hold on, Ed! What's the matter?!
It's Lt. Col. Hughes!
That was right after
we left Central, wasn't it?!
The bastard!
And yet, he kept us in the dark!
Did you know about this?!
I'm sorry. I just found out
about it myself not long ago.
In any case,
please go back inside!
You've got to be joking!
If Lt. Col. Hughes was killed,
then it was our fault!
And yet, he didn't even...
That's enough!
It's not as though he didn't tell you
just to be mean, you know.
I heard about this man Hughes.
I understand he was good to you.
But Mustang-san doesn't want you
to be thinking about revenge.
Maybe he was trying to say that you had
something more important to do.
Even so...
I've had it all wrong
this whole time.
I thought the Colonel didn't care what had happened to Brigadier General Hughes.
But maybe...
I'll become distinguished...
the most important in the country...
That was Mustang's
promise to him, after all.
In order to do that,
he sought for ways to get promoted, rather than dwell on personal feelings such as revenge.
The Colonel sure is an adult, huh?
How can that be?!
Someone dear to him was killed, and he knows who the culprit is.
Yet there's something even more important to him than avenging his friend's death.
Is that the way that adults act?!
You became a dog of the military
in order to achieve your goal, didn't you?
That bastard.
I really do hate him.
Someone's coming!
Don't be ridiculous.
This place is—
Who is it?
How good of you to come.
Unfortunately, the master is out.
Is that the body of
the girl named Lyra?
Well perceived,
Hohenheim of Light.
Sure enough, you were unable to forget me.
I heard her name
from my sons.
But even if I hadn't,
I would've known right away
from the scent of
your perfume.
Have you come here to
help me out, or something?
No, quite the opposite, Dante.
Gluttony!
I'll eat you!
I'm scared!
This one doesn't use a
transmutation circle either.
There's nothing to be
afraid of, Gluttony.
He has lived far too long
in that body.
He must be near its limit.
I am near my limit, it's true.
But the same thing
goes for you too.
Even if you can hide your
decaying body with clothing,
you cannot disguise the smell.
Hohenheim...
Dante,
do not mislead
my sons any further.
If you will promise me that,
I will tell you the reason why
your body has started to decay.
It looks like they successfully turned the military away.
I guess so.
Huh? Where's Ed?
He said there was something he had to do alone.
Forgive me...
Forgive me, Mom...
Fullmetal Alchemist...
Episode 45: "A Rotted Heart"
Al,
I'm going to fight.
You don't have to do
anything more now.